<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ziye&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ziye&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ziye.qiu3@gmail.com (Ziye)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ziye.qiu3@gmail.com (Ziye)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 23:51:53 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="http://ziyeqiu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 21:38:52 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>ziye.qiu3@gmail.com (Ziye)</author>
      <guid>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/about/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;银行咸鱼一条，暂居香港。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>井栏树村行纪-24年1月14日</title>
      <link>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20240114/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 23:51:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>ziye.qiu3@gmail.com (Ziye)</author>
      <guid>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20240114/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;之前在别人的游记里看到井栏树村路线能够俯瞰西贡的景色，很美，于是趁着周末去走走。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;井栏树村也是卫奕信径第四段的起点，但设置得十分隐蔽，一不留神就会走过头。从入口进入后，先是要在村庄里走一阵，可以看到许多低矮的自建房，有的正在施工，有的已经废弃了。我们经过时，正好听到有村民在大声地吼着“丢x”，一开始觉得好笑，但是随着吼声越来越大，就变得有点恐怖了。一行人加快脚步前进，走到自种庄稼的农田附近，就正式进入山里了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ziyeqiu.github.io/Users/hollyoak/ziyeqiu/static/20240114-01.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;20240114-01&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ziyeqiu.github.io/Users/hollyoak/ziyeqiu/static/20240114-02.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;20240114-02&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一开始是一路的下坡，这里是大片的林荫，且有梯级，尽管有些费膝盖但对体力要求不高，因此走到黃麖仔、大蓝湖村都是十分轻松的。感觉人类活动对这里生态的影响程度并不算大，路过的山涧都很清澈。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ziyeqiu.github.io/Users/hollyoak/ziyeqiu/static/20240114-03.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;20240114-03&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ziyeqiu.github.io/Users/hollyoak/ziyeqiu/static/20240114-04.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;20240114-04&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;走到牛寮后，就变得艰难了。从这里开始要沿着山脊爬升400多米到东洋山，其实如果只是梯级还好，爬就完事了，但有的路段并没有修缮完全——到达山顶的旧路因为存在山泥倾泻的风险，已经被禁用了，而新的路线不知道是不是预算不够，越修越敷衍，从一开始规整的石阶，到逐渐不规则的石阶，到最后连路都没了，只剩下一块没有植被的土地提醒你可以往这边走，不过其实也别无选择。于是我们就这样哼哧哼哧地登顶了，与我们一起登顶的还有一群东南亚人，只不过她们眉飞色舞地说笑，而我们累到静默。不过景色还是好看的，就是当天多云，拍出的照片也是灰蒙蒙的，没法有特别高的对比度——那得是出大太阳的时候才能拍到的。不过出大太阳就会很热，不是什么好事，尤其对这种没什么林荫的路径来说，就更糟了，所以这就叫“有舍必有得”，人生都是这样的，我悟了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ziyeqiu.github.io/Users/hollyoak/ziyeqiu/static/20240114-05.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;20240114-05&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ziyeqiu.github.io/Users/hollyoak/ziyeqiu/static/20240114-06.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;20240114-06&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ziyeqiu.github.io/Users/hollyoak/ziyeqiu/static/20240114-07.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;20240114-07&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ziyeqiu.github.io/Users/hollyoak/ziyeqiu/static/20240114-08.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;20240114-08&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;几张在山顶拍的照片，此时的我还以为最困难的路段已经结束了，真是太天真了！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;和修到一半疑似经费不足并半途而废的上山路径一样，下山的路径也是一滩碎石，但只有这个法子可以下山，于是胆战心惊地慢慢挪下山。还好前几天没有下雨，土壤不算湿滑，否则还是挺危险的。下山途中可以看到路旁放了一些碎石，用以防范暴雨时山泥倾泻带来的安全隐患和水土流失问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ziyeqiu.github.io/Users/hollyoak/ziyeqiu/static/20240114-09.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;20240114-09&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ziyeqiu.github.io/Users/hollyoak/ziyeqiu/static/20240114-10.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;20240114-09&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;直到碎石路段结束，看到石阶开始规律地出现，我们才真正松一口气。根据地图，往后都是比较平缓的下山路和车道了。卫奕信径第四段本来是从东洋山下来通过飞鹅山道-沙田坳道退出，但我带路的时候犯了错，一路沿着飞鹅山道下来了，发现后有点郁闷，因为这样最终会回到我们出发的彩虹站，相当于兜了一个圈，可见我的地理水平确实一般。不过后来和路人交谈得知两种路线都是行车道，而且路程用时也差不多，我才重新快乐起来。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ziyeqiu.github.io/Users/hollyoak/ziyeqiu/static/20240114-11.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;20240114-11&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如上图，黄色路线是我们这次的路线，蓝色为卫奕信径的官方路线，还是错得有点离谱哈。不过下山经过了一大片富人住宅，相当奢华，看到就是赚到，所以也算是意外的收获。看到好多狗、费用姐姐和鬼佬，鬼佬看不出来是哪家银行的MD，如果要找工作的话，直接朝他们递简历的成功率会比自己海投更高，我的看法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ziyeqiu.github.io/Users/hollyoak/ziyeqiu/static/20240114-12.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;20240114-12&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly market summary - Jan Week 01</title>
      <link>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20240107/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 23:51:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>ziye.qiu3@gmail.com (Ziye)</author>
      <guid>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20240107/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The performances of each asset classes are quite different from what they generally look like in the past 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though Asian stock performed well in last year end, its performances in the first week of January were not satisfying. With PMI statistics in China falling below expectation and reached its lowest in recent 6 months, stock indexes kept the falling trends in the whole week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, US stocks, especially tech indexes retreated a little bit, as tech giants, Apple, was downgraded because its largest end-market, China, is going through gloomy economy environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed income&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The minutes of FOMC in December came out, showing medium tone, and some economic statistics are actually better than estimation, traders have trimmed their bets on the rate cut to a more cautious one, resulting in drop in bonds last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Currency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In accordance with UST yields, dollar was rising for five consecutive days last week. Meanwhile, Yen retreated as an earthquake happened during the New Year Holiday, and it seems less likely for BoJ to exit its YCC policy in the short term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commodities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crude oil benefited from Red Sea crisis and levelled up tensions in Islamic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly market summary - Dec Week 02</title>
      <link>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231217/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 12:29:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>ziye.qiu3@gmail.com (Ziye)</author>
      <guid>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231217/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Currency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the Thursday&amp;rsquo;s Fed meeting, US CPI data came out and supported the strong dollar, where the central bank is anticipated to keep rates on hold. The expectation soon changed when the Fed’s “dot plot” indicated officials are expecting to lower rates by 75 basis points next year — a sharper pace of cuts than signalled in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USD/CNH opened higher on the back of strong US job data released last Friday night. The pairs traded between 7.0976 and 7.1997 during the week. In the earlier week the pairs were traded in good bid price but couldn’t break the 7.2000 strong resistance and it turned southward on the back of dovish comments from Powell and the Fed’s indication of 75 bps rate cut in 2024. After that, USD/CNH fell sharply to 7.1350 intraday low in Wednesday&amp;rsquo;s NYK trading session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BOE and ECB decided to hold the interest rates and indicating the high interest rates will maintain for a longer period, Dollar fell against EUR and GBP as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed income&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fed&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;dot plot&amp;rdquo; has strengthened market expectations for a rate cut, with the 10-year US bond yield falling below 4% for the first time since August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With year-end coming closer, foreign investors are seeking profit from CNY NCDs, benefiting from stronger CNY against USD as well as higher short-term interest rates in China. From end Nov until now, one-year CNY NCD rose to above 2.6%, as a result, many institutions entered through USD or HKD financing and invested in CNY NCDs after hedging the FX risks using swap, which implied a financing cost of around 1.5%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commodities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crude oil prices increased slightly, mainly benefiting from EIA&amp;rsquo;s reducing its forecasts on demand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly market summary - Dec Week 01</title>
      <link>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231210/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 12:29:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>ziye.qiu3@gmail.com (Ziye)</author>
      <guid>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231210/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Currency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USD/CNY fixing came relatively stable at around 7.11-7.12 areas in last week, indicating that the authority has no strong intention to push the currency stronger. In the meantime, USD/CNH was consolidated in a core range of 7.1250 - 7.1750 core range for the whole week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several important data related to China&amp;rsquo;s economy came out last week, including Caixin China PMI Composite, Caixin China PMI Services, and Trade Balance. Though the numbers were better than the market expectation and above the 50 watershed level, USD/CNH doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much reaction to it. Apart from that, Moody&amp;rsquo;s downgraded China&amp;rsquo;s sovereign credit rating from A1 to A1- did hit the CNH market and underpinning the USD/CNH afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yen outperformed its G10 peers last week, as investors piled on wagers the BoJ is set to tighten the YCC sooner rather than later, in response to comments from BoJ Kazuo Ueda that his job may become more challenging after year-end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed income&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overnight funding market sensed a sign of relief after seeing the SOFR dropped for second straight session as repo returns to normal. Nevertheless, funding costs tend to rise at the end of the month as banks pare their lending activity in the repo market to shore up their balance sheets for regulatory purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the week, market turned a blind eye on Jerome Powell’s attempt to curb bets on rate cuts. The bonds were still climbing on speculation the Fed will stay put this month and ease policy in 2024. While A pair of solid economic readings shook markets on Friday, with stocks rebounding on speculation the US will be able to skirt a recession. Now the flip side to that story is that bond traders were forced to trim their bets on rate cuts in 2024 — sending yields soaring. All around Wall Street, the prevailing view is: While economic strength makes many investors less apprehensive about a hard landing, it also implies the Federal Reserve might have to hold rates higher for longer. For Treasuries, that means an unwinding of the massive dovish trade that pointed to a Fed pivot as early as March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commodities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market was not reacting to OPEC+ commission on oil reduction and kept being worried about the over-supply issues, oil prices continued the downward trend for the week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly market summary - Nov Week 04</title>
      <link>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231126/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 12:29:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>ziye.qiu3@gmail.com (Ziye)</author>
      <guid>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231126/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Currency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3M HIBOR rose to its highest since 2001 this week, as year-end demand exacerbates an already-tight liquidity environment. Demand for the local currency is on the rise as lenders stockpile cash for regulatory purposes, sucking capital from the interbank system and pushed up the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, dollar continued the trends from last week, with Bloomberg Dollar Spot Index fell 0.2%, extending a 0.4% decline on Friday, largely led by USD/JPY and USD/CNH, as investors welcomed the prospects that Fed may be done raising interest rates. The dollar will keep current level and for a while before any new data came out to support US economy&amp;rsquo;s resilience. In the meantime, assets in emerging markets will keep being benefited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese government announced o set up a &amp;ldquo;white list&amp;rdquo; for its property developers, followed by allowing banks to offer short-term unsecured loans to eligible property developers in the list, which is likely to stabilise the economy and the performance of CNH. Nevertheless, reaction from the market and implementation taken by banks remain key to the success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed income&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 30 year UST auction went ok and the UST yields dipped further after the auction, while the German, Italy, France, Nordics may not reach the end of the rate hikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economic stats raised concerns on a successful soft landing, which turned into negative premium on 10-year UST. The premium usually served as an instrument to hedge the inflation and unforeseeable uncertainties like supply-demand shock, its decrease indicate that investors put higher possibility in a potential recession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commodities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crude oil recorded a decline this week, with markets began to doubt whether the OPEC+ had reached an agreement on supply cut as the meeting scheduled on Thursday was delayed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly market summary - Nov Week 03</title>
      <link>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231119/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 12:29:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>ziye.qiu3@gmail.com (Ziye)</author>
      <guid>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231119/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Currency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dollar went through huge changes last week after the weak CPI stats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Monday to Tuesday, USD/CNH was trading at around 7.3100 and agents were buying short-term funding in the market as usual. Some talks about the improving relationships between US and China and China stopped purchase freeze of Boeing sent USD/CNH lower, in the meantime, the lower UST yields and USD/JPY also contributed to softer dollar. During days ahead of the US CPI data and Xi Biden meeting in APEC, the USD/CNH was generally trading between 7.29 and 7.31.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the weaker than expected US CPI data was released, which indicated that the US rate hike cycle may come to an end. The market consensus is now expecting the first rate cut in May 2024, USD/CNH soon plunged down toward 7.25. Bloomberg dollar spot index fell by 0.3%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of dollar&amp;rsquo;s plunge, major currencies in asian economies were performing well.
Before any new data came out to support US economy’s resilience, dollar will remain soft and benefit currencies and assets in emerging markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed income&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the result of lower-than-expected CPI and PPI data, the market has diverged to the consensus that US economy was cooling down and the rate hike may already come to an end, or at least soon, driving the yields down by around 2-14bps, which also benefit the performance of equity markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commodity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday, crude oil stepped into bear market with its price declined by more than 20% compared to its September highest point, mainly because the market is worried about 1) swelling supply indicated by EIA data; 2)overall weakening demand; 3)shorting behaviours enlarged by algorithm trading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly market summary - Nov Week 01</title>
      <link>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231105/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 12:29:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>ziye.qiu3@gmail.com (Ziye)</author>
      <guid>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231105/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed income&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BoJ loosened its YCC policy by adding more flexibility to it, allowing the  yields to exceed 1%. In the meantime, it announced its 2024 inflation expectation, which signal its preparing to exit the negative interest rate policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After NonFarm data was published this Friday, which was below market expectation, yields decreased, serving as a Halloween gift for investors holding long positions in bonds. In the meantime, equity market increased, mainly because the market price-in the expectation that no further rate hikes will increase this year. Also, Bill Ackman&amp;rsquo;s announcement that he closed the short positions in bond may intrigue a flow of investors to close out the short positions. The market is reacting drastically against the below-expectation data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equity market also benefited from the decreasing yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Currency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unexpectedly, Yen weakened after BoJ announced its new decision, further breached 150 after BoJ announced its decision, mainly because the market was putting too high expectation on BoJ&amp;rsquo;s potential policy move (1.5% or to abandon YCC policy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dollar was also weakened, falling to its lowest since September as the Fed meeting and Treasury refunding announcement plunged following the cooler-than-expected US jobs and ISM services data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commodity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the week, WTI Crude oil was seeing sharp losses, mainly due to worries on the US economy, the largest oil consumer, after the release of weak labor market and economy data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly market summary - Oct Week 02</title>
      <link>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231029/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 12:29:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>ziye.qiu3@gmail.com (Ziye)</author>
      <guid>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231029/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed income&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gruelling selloff in UST that began since the summer continues, most notably in the longer end of the yield curve. On Monday, the treasury yield breached 5%, a level not seen since 2007 and an increase of about 125bps since the trough in July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the selloff continues, markets are putting spotlight on the largest missing buyer: the Fed. The Fed is shrinking its portfolio of government securities at $720 billion annual pace, making the Treasury Department’s job of funding a near -$2 trillion federal deficits all the harder. The concerns on the debt ratio kept going.
Which, in turn, will affect the future supply of UST.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equity market was also affected by higher yields in bond market, as it attracts money that might otherwise get invested in equity market. As yields surged in September, the S&amp;amp;P 500 fell about 4.5%, despite relatively positive economic data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, yields didn&amp;rsquo;t sustain long above 5% and maintained at a level around 4.8% - 4.9% on Friday close, the market starts to prepare for the coming important meetings and data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s been optimism in corporate credit, as it outperform other assets in the past few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Currency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USD/CNY: USD didn&amp;rsquo;t go for stronger, de-risking is waning. It&amp;rsquo;s been a week with relatively low volatility, mainly driven by treasury yields and surprises on growth data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPY/USD breached 150 on Monday, which may affect BoJ&amp;rsquo;s opinion on whether to maintain YCC policy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly market summary - Oct Week 02</title>
      <link>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 12:29:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>ziye.qiu3@gmail.com (Ziye)</author>
      <guid>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231022/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week&amp;rsquo;s spotlight was still the violence and the conflict between Israel and Gaza Strip, while there was no significant progress in the conflict so the flows remained volatile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commodities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effects of the conflicts can be clearly seen in the prices of commodities like crude oil, which is about 10% higher now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gold also increased by around 2% over the week, and once reached over the point of $2000. For gold, it has the same macroeconomic implications with 10-Year UST, affected by economic growth, inflation rate, and liquidity, also showing the global investors&amp;rsquo; preferences for risky assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed income&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both derisking flows and selloffs are affecting the treasury market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 10-year U.S. Treasury yield hit 16-year highs, but soon recovered from the peak 5%, down to 4.83%. The higher for longer expectation was further confirmed by Powell&amp;rsquo;s  speech last week, which is supposed to be the last public communication before the FOMC on 1st Nov, suggesting further hikes could be needed if sustained economic growth drives more persistent inflation, but no clear messages on if there will be another hike, the consensus are gambling on decreased possibility of a near hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are concerns over the debt ratio, which may not remain the pervious level since the end of COVID due to strong growth in GDP. Now the economy seems to be at its peak (jobless rate is at historically low level) and is expected to be slow, the deficits are still high and are expecting to go higher, a resumption of the upward trend seems inevitable. While it&amp;rsquo;s not at a crisis level yet, which can be seen from the status of dollar in the global foreign exchange market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dollar dropped approaching October&amp;rsquo;s lows and under the important 30-day moving average support line. Falling Treasury rates last week caused the market to gamble on the decreasing likelihood of a recent Fed hike and for dollar to lose appeal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly market summary - Oct Week 02</title>
      <link>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 12:29:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>ziye.qiu3@gmail.com (Ziye)</author>
      <guid>http://ziyeqiu.github.io/post/20231015/</guid>
      
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fixed income&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After last Friday&amp;rsquo;s hotter-than-expected economic data, market participants have built the expectations that the US Treasury rates will stay higher-for-longer, letting the 10-year US Treasuries to hit an intraday peak of 4.88% on Friday, a fresh 16-year-high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the following Monday, treasury yields fell, mainly due to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The break out of Hamas Attack, demand for treasuries increased because of risk aversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several speakers from Federal Reserve came out and stated that the current yield increase could potentially eased the need for another rate hike, resulting into market consensus that Fed rate hike might be done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several economic statistics and minutes this week also affect Treasuries through supply and demand dynamics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;11 Oct, both US PPI and core PPI are higher-than-expected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FOMC minutes expressed conflicting opinions about rate hikes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;13 Oct, CPI remained unchanged compared to August, but core CPI slowed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past few weeks provided a good example on how treasury yields are affected by several factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supply and demand dynamic.&lt;/strong&gt; The higher-than-expected supply of Treasury securities to fund US fiscal deficits were well absorbed by market demand, though at high prices. However, increasing demand from risk aversion and new market consensus drove the yield down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inflation expectation.&lt;/strong&gt; Unchanged or slow down numbers let the inflation expectation remain contained.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic performance.&lt;/strong&gt; US economy&amp;rsquo;s resilient performances &amp;lsquo;surprised&amp;rsquo; participants and affecting their (as well as the Fed&amp;rsquo;s) bet on the odds of future rate hikes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dollar&amp;rsquo;s performance is also closely related to Fed speech and geopolitical tensions this week, where risk aversion let funds fly to safe haven currencies (dollar and yen this time) and Fed&amp;rsquo;s potential hint put dollar under selling pressure, making divergent impacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On sight of PPI data, dollar climbed in choppy trade first while soon dropped back as more attention was focused on tepid core inflation readings. Thursday, the release of CPI data pulled the market&amp;rsquo;s consensus a little back to &amp;lsquo;higher-for-longer&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commodities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gold, crude oil, and even metals, all benefited from geopolitical conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
